this video is gonna be about why a
little bit about why capitalism is not
the answer to our problems it's kind of
causing most of the problems but to me
the inefficiency of if you have a
solution either a better product than
what's out there or a brand new product
or service there are so many steps you
have to follow in order to allow it to
be the solution so it's actually on the
market when it's just an idea in your
head it's not helping anyone so not only
do you have to come up with the idea
which is probably the easy part
you then have to either be the person
who can actually create it in my case I
have a lot of ideas for technology but I
don't know how to code and I'm trying to
learn it and my brain will not learn
coding so there's ways around that of
course you can outsource it I can pay
someone to make an app which I'm
planning on doing for my first project
but just like you either need to have
the skill to be able to make it or have
the resources to be able to to pay for
it and then you have to be able to
market it and then it's kind of the
point in the system where you figure out
if it's actually feasible if people are
going if it's gonna resonate with people
and that process works okay for some
people the type-a personalities and the
entrepreneurial types who love risk and
love but and if that was the only
problem the only issue on the planet was
that it didn't have enough money like me
personally do not know money then maybe
I could fight and do that but figuring
out but I don't if like if I just had an
idea for a better mousetrap and the
world didn't need that answer it was
just about making myself more money then
yeah that system works for a specific
group of people but what about the rest
of us what about people who have ideas
to save the planet new energy systems
and new ways of combating disease and
not only do they have to go through that
process they're already doing it in a
world where it's against them where you
have to mark it possibly in a market
that isn't that's already saturated so
even if you have an amazing brilliant
idea if it's for a car chances of you
getting it made and getting it be
successful because in order to start a
car company would need tens of billions
of dollars and it's really hard to break
into that market when people spend
millions of dollars on advertising the
big car companies so one of the reasons
to me the global cooperative is the
solution is I want the system in place
to be able to go online and give my idea
offer it to the world and have people
comment on it and critique it and have
it there's so much that that offers one
you get to find out a lot of the
problems and issues the potential users
would have before it's ever made to you
have that's not number these you don't
need to be the personality Taiyo table
to make it because the chance of being
both of those people is smaller than
just needing one of those that there's
the people who will know the steps to
take there are people who would love
every step along that process so maybe
one person loved all the steps but like
someone loves marketing and somebody
loves running the data and figuring out
the analysis people love coding so
allowing people to give what they want
to give and not have to be all things at
once in order to be I mean in order to
be the CEO or the start of a company the
person who starts a company sorry you
need to be a jack-of-all-trades you need
to know how to market to do HR to do all
of that and where you don't know if your
business fails and a lot of obstacles
come up I've seen it happen with many of
my friends and family and so being able
to offer that
system that helps us to go from idea
through to either no this isn't gonna
work or like wow what an amazing product
maybe in between figuring that out
together I just think there's so much
power there and then when you're you own
it together so you're not one person
taking on all the risk because there's
people like me who are risk adverse I
would stress me out if I didn't know
where my next paycheck was coming on
from and I have issues with be able to
make a decision
I concede this infinite world in front
of me and all the different ways to do
something I need other people who maybe
don't have that vision of the big
picture but do you have the vision of
life like our more decisive than big
things so I think where we fall short in
skills other people can pick it up we
can spread the reward and risk oh well
maybe there isn't really like the reward
is in using the product in service in
using what we created together because
it's a solution that's the reward for
the user and you're spreading the risk
oh you're not one person putting in ten
million dollars to see if you're gonna
make it big that system exists it's
capitalism if you want have an idea that
you think is gonna make it there go
ahead and make it there but if you have
an idea that you just want a gift to the
world you want to have the world make
better and create together and you want
us all to own it I want there to be a
space online for us to do that and so
that's what the global cooperative is
gonna be it's gonna be one of probably
not the first project maybe not even the
first couple as we work through a system
to create together but very soon on to
be able to have a online hub to go on to
and offer suggestions to improve
existing technology as well as create
brand new technology and working through
that whole process together and being
able to lift each other up where we fall
short and I think I want that assistant
to exist and hopefully other people can
see the beauty - thank you